(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
不知火フレア 2ND ANNIVERSARY LIVE!
～みんなで沢山盛り上がろう！～
Shiranui Flare 2nd Anniversary Live!
~Let's all have a great time!~
Yeah...
やっとさ幕開けだ ほら寄って たかって お手拝借
Finally, the curtain's rising! Come one, come all, give us a hand!
スタートラインに立った今 そう武装 ほうそう 構想で登場
Now that I'm at the starting line, dressed up, ready for the broadcast and concept!
ここは遊び心で満ちよう 合図で策略なのだらららら
Let's fill this place with playfulness! On signal, it's a strategy, la-la-la-la!
一人でも多くの招き猫がいるなら 正すことから始めましょう
If there's even one more beckoning cat here, let's start by putting things right!
幸せな時間を どれだけ過ごせるかは
How much happy time we can spend together depends...
微々たるものでも愛に気付けるか さあ試されよう
...on whether we can notice love in even the smallest things. Come, let's be tested!
パッパッパ 晴れた街に チャッチャッチャ 跳ねる心
Pa-pa-pa, in the sunny town! Cha-cha-cha, a bouncing heart!
一人じゃないと否定できるように 僕は探すんだ
I'll search, so I can deny being alone!
Yeah!
静けさと一体 一層 風向きを お手拝借
One with the silence, let's change the wind's direction even more, give us a hand!
スタート合図は鳴り止まなく 僕の怒涛の序章と
The starting signal won't stop ringing; it's the prologue to my surge!
ここは時既に戦の場 煽りを付けるなら 何がハラ?
This place is already a battlefield; if you're gonna stir things up, what's at stake?
一人でも多く嘆き方がなくなるなら なで肩ブームでいいでしょう
If it makes even one person stop lamenting, a sloping shoulder boom is fine!
忘れたくないな 追風に増やせるかだ
I don't want to forget; it's about whether we can increase it with the tailwind!
微々たるものでも愛に気付けるなら スタートに戻ろう
If we can notice love even in small things, let's go back to the start!
パッパッパ 晴れた街に チャッチャッチャ 跳ねる心
Pa-pa-pa, in the sunny town! Cha-cha-cha, a bouncing heart!
一人じゃないと否定してくれる あなたを僕は探すんだ
I'll search for you, the one who denies that I'm alone!
Ah ya you can we can だ
Ah ya, you can, we can!
耳にタコができるほど聞いた アイラブユーの言葉だって
Even those 'I love you's I've heard until my ears were calloused...
どこから信じればいいの?
...where should I start believing them from?
箱に荷物を詰めただけ 気持ちが軽くなったようだ
Just by packing things into a box, my heart feels lighter.
哀しみも仕舞うべき 懐に仕舞うべきだ
I should tuck away the sadness too, keep it in my pocket.
幸せと思える貴重な時間を どれだけ過ごせるかは
How much precious time we can spend feeling happy depends...
Ah いつでもスタートだよ
Ah, it's always a start!
パッパッパ 晴れた街に パッパッパ 晴れた笑顔
Pa-pa-pa, in the sunny town! Pa-pa-pa, a sunny smile!
一人じゃないと否定できるように
So I can deny that I'm alone!
パッパッパ 晴れた街に パッパッパ 晴れた笑顔
Pa-pa-pa, in the sunny town! Pa-pa-pa, a sunny smile!
一人じゃないと否定できるように 僕は探すんだ
I'll search, so I can deny being alone!
一人じゃないと否定してくれる あなたを僕は探すんだ
I'll search for you, the one who denies that I'm alone!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
皆さん、こんふれー！不知火フレアです！
Konfure, everyone! I'm Shiranui Flare!
不知火フレア2周年記念ライブへようこそ！
Welcome to Shiranui Flare's 2nd Anniversary Live!
一曲目は『StaRt』を歌わせていただきました！
For the first song, I sang 'StaRt'!
今日は最後まで楽しんでいってねー！
Please enjoy the show until the very end today!
それでは、次の曲！
Now then, on to the next song!
La la la...
笑って行こう どこまでも
Let's keep on smiling, wherever we go.
君の笑顔が見たいから
Because I want to see your smile.
一歩ずつ踏み出して
Taking it one step at a time.
明日へと繋げよう
Let's connect it to tomorrow.
Smile & Go!!
...できるように明日も歌うんだ
...so that I can do it, I'll sing again tomorrow
はーい！
Hiii!
みんな、こんぬーい！
Everyone, Konnui!
ホロライブ三期生の不知火フレアです！どうもー！
I'm Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd Gen! Hello!
この度は私の二周年ライブに、
Thank you so much for coming to my
二周年記念ライブにお越しいただきまして、
誠に、誠にありがとうございます！
2nd anniversary live, my 2nd anniversary
commemorative live today!
みんな元気？
Is everyone doing well?
お、見てるね、見てるね。ありがとね、ありがとね。
Oh, you're watching, you're watching.
Thank you, thank you.
一階席、二階席、アリ... アリーナは一階席だ。
よろしくね！
First floor, second floor, are... the arena is the
first floor. Nice to meet you!
今日はね、たくさんたくさん歌っていきます。
Today, I'm going to sing a lot of songs.
あの、なんか結構ね、セトリ詰め詰めになってしまったので、
割とあの淡々とトークしていきますよ。
The setlist ended up being quite packed, so I'll be
talking somewhat briskly.
ということでですね、あのここから先たくさんあの歌っていきますので、
ぜひぜひ楽しんでください。
So, I'll be singing many songs from here on out,
so please enjoy!
ハッシュタグ、こちら。ちょっと待ってね。
The hashtag is here. Wait a second.
これ！ #不知火フレア2周年記念ライブ
こちらよかったら、いっぱいツイートしてくれたら嬉しいです！
This! #ShiranuiFlare2ndAnniversaryLive
Please tweet a lot about it if you'd like!
目指せ、トレンド一位！よろしくお願いします！
Aiming for trending number one! Thank you!
ということで、セカンドアニバーサリーライブ、
みんなで盛り上がろうというサブタイを呟きつつ、
So, while tweeting the subtitle 'Let's all get
hyped up' for the Second Anniversary Live,
大声で叫びつつ、次の曲を歌っていくんですけど、
and shouting it out, I'm going to sing the next
song.
次はあの、もう一曲私のソロ曲を聴いてもらった後、
えーと続けてコラボかな？
Next, after you listen to one more of my solo
songs, will it be a collaboration next?
続けてあの、コラボパートに移っていきますのでね、
あの楽しんでくださいね。
We'll be moving on to the collaboration part after
that, so please look forward to it.
はい、ということで皆さん、いいですか？あの、あれですよ。
Alright, everyone, are you ready? It's that song.
次の曲は、やっぱり私のね、お約束ということで、
いきなり来ちゃいますよ。いきますよ。
The next song is, as expected of me,
coming up suddenly. Here we go!
それでは聞いてください。Smile and Go!
Please listen: Smile and Go!
こんぬーい！準備はいいか？
Konnui! Are you ready?
今日はみんなで騒ぎましょう！せーの！
Let's make some noise together today! One, two!
はい！はい！はい！はいはい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai-hai!
やって来ました みんなに会える時間で
The time has finally come for me to see everyone
歌、公開ゲームとか見て欲しくて
I want you to see my singing and public games
配信五分前です ごめんなさい
It's five minutes before the stream, I'm sorry
あっという間に過ぎてしまう毎日に
In days that pass by in the blink of an eye
乗り遅れないように手繋ごう
Let's hold hands so we don't fall behind
一歩ずつだって一緒にいよう
Even if it's one step at a time, let's be together
気付けば隣にいてくれてありがとう
Thank you for being by my side before I even realized it
どんな高い壁だってひとっ飛びで飛び越えて
No matter how high the wall, I'll leap over it in a jump
誰も見たことない世界に みんなで行こうよ
Let's all go to a world no one has ever seen
君とSmile and Go! 楽しんだもん勝ち
Smile and Go! with you, whoever has most fun wins
君とSmile and Go! 弾けたもん勝ち
Smile and Go! with you, whoever gets most hyped wins
ここに笑顔で集まれば
If we gather here with smiles
最高テンション
Maximum tension
僕らSmile and Go! いつも全力で
We're Smile and Go! Always giving it our all
僕らSmile and Go! 遊びまくろうぜ
We're Smile and Go! Let's play around a lot
だってこの日常が
Because this daily life
大切な宝物だよ Smile and Go!
is a precious treasure! Smile and Go!
雑談配信 今日はまったり行きましょう
Let's have a relaxing chat stream today
たわいもない話 聞いて欲しくて
聞いてよちょっと、聞いてよ
I want you to listen to my idle talk
Listen, just listen for a bit
たまにはお休みしようと思ったけれど
I thought about taking a break once in a while, but...
やっぱり晩酌配信しちゃおうかな
Maybe I'll do a late-night drinking stream after all
用意ができたよ 乾杯！
It's all ready, cheers!
ありふれたこの時も 一緒に過ごしたら
Even these common moments, if we spend them together...
いつの間にかキラキラと 何よりも輝いて
They'll sparkle before we know it, shining brighter
言葉にはできない思いが 溢れ出してきちゃうよ
君とレッツゴー
Feelings that can't be put into words overflow
Let's go with you
歌ってみようよ
Let's try singing
君と Let's enjoy!
With you, let's enjoy!
心は一つに
Our hearts as one
どこにいたって 優しさは
No matter where you are, kindness
届いているよ
is reaching you
僕ら Let's enjoy!
We, let's enjoy!
テンション上げてさ
Raise the tension
僕ら Let's enjoy!
We, let's enjoy!
はしゃぎまくろう
Let's frolic around
きっと
Surely
明日はもっと 楽しいこと
Tomorrow more fun things
待っているから
are waiting for you
2周年！
2nd anniversary!
みんな本当にありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much!
まだまだこの先も
I still want to
みんなとたくさん盛り上がりたいから！
get hyped with everyone a lot more from here on!
最後までちゃんとついてきてね！
Make sure to keep up with me until the very end!
手拍子！
Clap your hands!
はい！ はい！ はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai!
せーの！
Ready!
一緒に！
Together!
3, 2, 1, Go!
ずっと見ていて
Keep watching me
私のことを
これから先も
From now on,
期待してね
expect a lot
予測不能な ワクワクを
Unpredictable excitement
君に送るから
I'll send to you
君と Smile and Go!!!
With you, Smile and Go!!!
楽しんだもん勝ち
The one who enjoys it wins
君と Smile and Go!!!
With you, Smile and Go!!!
弾けたもん勝ち
The one who pops wins
ここに笑顔で集まれば
If we gather here with smiles
最高のテンション
the best tension
僕ら Smile and Go!!!
We, Smile and Go!!!
もう全力で
With all our might
僕ら Smile and Go!!!
We, Smile and Go!!!
遊びまくろう
Let's play around
だって
Because
この日常が 大切な
this daily life is a precious
宝物だよ
treasure
とびきりの笑顔で行こう
Let's go with a superb smile
Smile and Go!
はあ、なんかベースだけだと寂しいな
Sigh, it's lonely with just the bass.
誰か一緒に弾いてくんないかなー？
I wonder if someone will play with me?
パトラー！
Patra!
お、フレアー！
Oh, Flare!
ベース、あ、ギター弾けないけど
I can't play the bass, ah, guitar, but
来ちゃったぜ！
I came anyway!
な、名前間違えたよ！
You got the name wrong!
え、弾けないけど持ってきてくれたの？
Eh, you brought it even though you can't play?
そうだよ、なんかパトラがどうしてもって言うからさ
Yeah, because Patra said she really wanted me to.
おおー
Ohhh
ちょっと持ってくるだけ持ってきてみた
I just tried bringing it along.
じゃあセッションしようよ！
Then let's have a session!
ベベン！
Beben!
2周年おめでとう！ウェイ！
Happy 2nd Anniversary! Yay!
ありがとう、パトラもおめでとう！
Thanks, happy anniversary to you too, Patra!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ウェイ！
Yay!
パトラもおめでとってなんだよ！
What do you mean "happy anniversary to Patra too"!
パトラもデビュー、あれ3周年？
Patra's debut, was it 3rd anniversary?
あ、そうなんです
Ah, that's right.
おめでとうございます
Congratulations.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
いやー、本当おめでたいよ
Man, it's really worth celebrating.
ありがとね、お互いね。めでたいということで
Thank you, for both of us. It's a happy occasion.
本当本当本当
Really, really, really.
全然関係ない曲を
I had Patra play
ちょっとパトラに弾いていただいたので、一緒に歌いたいなと思ってます！
a completely unrelated song, so I'd like to sing it together!
い、関係なくないよ、あの歌は！
I-It's not unrelated, that song!
もう我々というか、
It's already like us,
まあフレアを表した、ものすごく...
or rather, it represents Flare, very much...
どういう意味だよ！意味わかんねえからな今！
What does that mean! I don't get the meaning right now!
今回歌う曲はパトラが弾いてくれたので、
Since Patra played the song we're singing this time,
パトラはガチで弾いてます
Patra is playing for real.
あ、はい！弾きました！
Ah, yes! I played it!
で、私の方はエアギターとなっております！
And for my part, it's air guitar!
でもなんか決まってんだよね！
But you look like you're nailing it!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ほら超かっこいいんだけど
Look, you're super cool.
はい、ということで、ぜひぜひ聴いてください！いきますよ！
Yes, so please listen to it! Here we go!
はい！
Yes!
かわいE！
Kawai E!
かわいE 作詞・作曲 こやまたくや
Kawai E Lyrics/Composition: Koyama Takuya
今日も駅の改札前でやけに
Today too, looking at the couple flirting
いちゃいちゃしてるカップル見て凹む
excessively in front of the station gates makes me depressed
地味にありゃりゃ 周りを見りゃ
It's plain "oh my", looking around me,
憧れんけどちょっと羨ましい
I don't aspire to it but it's a bit enviable
30越えたらモテ始めるって先輩の言葉だけ信じて
I only believe my senior's words that I'll start being popular after I'm over 30
ルーティン・ワーク 特筆要素は無い
Routine work, no noteworthy elements,
これはいかんわなんとかせんとあかん
this is no good, I gotta do something
飽きたふりしてダラリと過ごしていたら
While I was pretending to be bored and lounging around,
運命の出会いさ
a fateful encounter
あんたに出会ったんや
I met you,
ちゃんと気持ち伝えへんと行けへんなあ
I gotta tell you my feelings properly
君はかわいE 越してかわFやんけ
You're beyond Cute-E, you're Cute-F
魅力溢れてこぼれるやんけ
Your charm is overflowing and spilling out
恥ずかし越して恥ずかZやんけ
Beyond embarrassment, it's Embarrass-Z
気持ちええ越して気持ちFやんけ
Beyond feeling good, it's feeling Good-F
かわいE 越してかわFやんけ
Beyond Cute-E, you're Cute-F
魅力溢れてこぼれるやんけ
Your charm is overflowing and spilling out
楽しい越して楽しZやんけ
Beyond fun, it's Fun-Z
嬉しい越して嬉しZやんかいな
Beyond happy, it's Happy-Z
今日も駅のエレベーターでやけに
Today too, looking at the couple flirting
いちゃいちゃしてるカップル見て凹む
excessively in the station elevator makes me depressed
君は E E E E 越えてやっぱ超 F やんけ
You're beyond E E E E, and totally super F.
君はちょいちょいちょいちょい 越えてやっぱ超 F やんけ
You're passing bit by bit, and totally super F.
どんな理論や ほんまにすごいわ
What kind of logic is that? It's truly amazing.
なんかええ感じに聞こえてくるやんか
It's starting to sound pretty good, isn't it?
あっち立てたふりしてたら 1人過ごしてたら 運命の出会い
While pretending to be over there, while spending time alone, a fateful encounter.
愛やら恋やら言いたくないなら 別の言葉探して歌おう
If you don't want to say things like love or passion, let's find other words and sing.
君はカッコイイ越えてカッコ F やんけ 魅力溢れてこぼれるやんけ
You're beyond 'Cool' and totally 'Cool-F'. Your charm is overflowing.
ハズい越えてハズ D やんけ 気持ちいい越えて気持ち F やんけ
Beyond 'Embarrassing', you're totally 'Hazu-D'. Beyond 'Feeling good', you're totally 'Kimochi-F'.
カッコイイ越えてカッコ F やんけ 魅力溢れてこぼれるやんけ
You're beyond 'Cool' and totally 'Cool-F'. Your charm is overflowing.
楽しい越えてたの D やんけ 嬉しい D E F G H I...
Beyond 'Fun', you're totally 'Tano-D'. 'Happy' D E F G H I...
待ってぬるくて腐ってとろけそう 踊れそうなソングテレササイニン
Wait, it's lukewarm and rotting. A song that makes you want to dance, Teresa Signing.
カッコ決めて歌ってみたいけど まだふざけていたい ギリギリ反感
I want to try singing with a cool pose, but I still want to fool around. On the edge of antipathy.
それっぽい言葉それっぽく俺が 並べても伝わらないから今日は
Even if I arrange plausible words in a plausible way, they won't get through, so today...
アルファベットを使った古典的な 表現で挑む最後の平成
I'll challenge with a classical expression using the alphabet. The last Heisei.
君は可愛い越えてカワ F やんけ 魅力溢れてこぼれるやんけ
Beyond 'Cute', you're totally 'Kawa-F'. Your charm is overflowing.
ハズい越えてハズ D やんけ 気持ちいい越えて気持ち F やんけ
Beyond 'Embarrassing', you're totally 'Hazu-D'. Beyond 'Feeling good', you're totally 'Kimochi-F'.
可愛い越えてカワ F やんけ 魅力溢れてこぼれるやんけ
Beyond 'Cute', you're totally 'Kawa-F'. Your charm is overflowing.
ハズい越えてハズ D やんけ 気持ちいい越えて気持ち F やんけ
Beyond 'Embarrassing', you're totally 'Hazu-D'. Beyond 'Feeling good', you're totally 'Kimochi-F'.
カッコイイ越えてカッコ F やんけ 魅力溢れてこぼれるやんけ
Beyond 'Cool', you're totally 'Cool-F'. Your charm is overflowing.
恋しい越えてこい D やんけ 嬉しい D E F G H I...
Beyond 'Longing', you're totally 'Koi-D'. 'Happy' D E F G H I...
もう楽しいけどちょっとトゲがある 毎日を目指す本音
It's already fun, but there's a bit of a thorn. My true feelings aim for every day.
ラップじゃない 知らん合間に フォーリンラブ ええ感じ 越えて F 感じやねー
It's not rap. Before I knew it, falling in love. Beyond a good feeling, it's an F feeling, right?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ギター上手いやんけ！
You're good at guitar!
本当？腱鞘炎になりそう。
Really? I feel like I'm getting tendonitis.
え？あとパトラさんなんかベース上手ですね。
Eh? Also, Patra-san, you're good at bass.
ベースはあのお腹の上にね、こうももも寄せながらやってた。
For the bass, I was doing it like this, bringing it close to my stomach.
ガチじゃん。
You're serious.
いや、でも今日はね、本当にありがとうございました。記念撮影しようよ、せっかく。
No, but really, thank you so much for today. Let's take a commemorative photo since we're here.
あれ？なんか身長差ちょっとおかしい...
Wait? The height difference is a bit weird...
私とパトラ2cmしか違わないはずなんですけどパトラ...
There's only supposed to be a 2cm difference between me and Patra, but Patra...
あ、角が当たる。ちょっと下がった方がいいか。こう、こう、こう、どう？
Ah, the horns are touching. Maybe I should lower a bit. Like this, like this, like this, how's that?
微調整。いっぱい撮って！いっぱい撮って！
Fine-tuning. Take lots of photos! Take lots of photos!
うん。そして、あ、パトラさん何か今日は、あ、お話ししておきたいことがあるとか。
Yeah. And, ah, Patra-san, do you have something you want to talk about today?
おねフレアの、ちょっとね記念はこう、っていうのもあれなんですけど、8月10日、周パトラ誕生日でございます！
It's Flare's anniversary, and it's a bit awkward to say this now, but August 10th is Suapatora's birthday!
おー！そりゃそうだよね、こんなね、あの周パトラさんがね、なんの予定もないのに来てくれるわけがないんですよ！
Oh! That makes sense! There's no way Suapatora-san would come here without any plans!
番宣しに来たんだな！？
You came here to promote yourself, didn't you!?
ありがとうございます。お誕生日、パトラは、あのねノエフレ派なんだけど、え、もう本当にそれこそフレアを心底からね、あの、お友達だと思ってるからマジで。
Thank you. For your birthday... Patra is a Noe-Flare fan, but she truly, from the bottom of her heart, thinks of Flare as a friend, seriously.
お友達だと思ってるよ。あの、この曲もね、あの、あれですよ、私とパトラの曲ではないので。
I think of you as a friend. Um, this song too, well, it's not a song for me and Patra.
え、ちょ待って、そこに愛はあるのかい！？ねえ、ねえ、ねえ！？
Wait, wait, is there love there!? Hey, hey, hey!?
愛嬌と、あの友達という名の、お、も、ちゃ、ではあるんだけどね。
There's charm, and well, what's called a friend, you are a t-o-y, though.
パトラ、ありがとうねパトラ。
Patra, thank you, Patra.
あ、ありがとうございましたー！このライブ最高！わー！
Ah, thank you so much! This live is the best! Wah!
マリン！ノエルちゃーん！マリー！
Marine! Noel-chan! Marie!
あれ？マリちゃん？なんか、つまんねーや。
Wait? Mari-chan? This is kind of... boring.
あれ？フレア。なんかさ、マリンもつまんねーなって思ってたんだけど。
Huh? Flare... You know, Marine was also thinking it's boring.
フレアがいないとつまんないね。
It's boring without Flare, isn't it?
もう つまんないんだけど
It's so boring...
何よー おもんなー
What's that? Boring?
うーん全然全然全然
No, no, no, not at all...
ちょっとフレア早く来い！
Hey Flare, come here quick!
来いよ！
Come on!
なんかプンプンなんだけど
I'm like, sulking...
やめなさい。やめなさい。やめなさい。
Stop it. Stop it. Stop it.
あれ？おかしいな...
Huh? That's strange...
おかしいな。こんなはずじゃなかったんだけどな。
That's strange. It wasn't supposed to be like this.
はい！
Yes!
はい、ということでね、
Alright, so,
どうも2人とも、いつめんです！
Thank you both, we're Itsumen!
いつめんです！ありがとうございます！
We're Itsumen! Thank you!
はい。ここはどこですか？なんか見たことあるね。
Yes. Where are we? It looks familiar.
あれなーここ。団長ここ知ってるよ。
This place... Dancho knows this place.
どこですか？
Where is it?
ここ、あの、海。
This is, um, the sea.
そうだね。海だけどね。
That's true. It is the sea.
ここ知ってる。団長ここで歌ったことあるよ。
I know this place. Dancho has sung here before.
そうだね。そうなんだよ。ここは、ま、ノエちゃんが100万人の時に歌ったり、
Right. That's right. This is, well, where Noel-chan sang during her 1M sub stream,
あとSSSとかね。
and SSS and stuff.
あー、そうそうそう。ビーチ、ビーチ。
Ah, yeah yeah. The beach, the beach.
そこのビーチでちょっと歌いたい曲があったので、
Since there was a song I wanted to sing on this beach,
で、3人で歌いたいなってずっと言ってた曲があったの。
there was a song I've been saying I wanted to sing with the three of us.
何だろう。
I wonder what it is.
なので今日は歌おうかなと思って。ちょっと高いけど、大丈夫かな？2人。
So I thought we'd sing it today. It's a bit high, but are you two okay?
大丈夫です！
I'm okay!
団長も大丈夫です！
Dancho is also okay!
ま、ノエちゃんは音程の方が心配だね。
Well, for Noel-chan, the pitch is more of a concern.
ま、そうだね。もうそれはどうしようも...
Well, yeah. There's nothing I can do about that...
じゃあですね。早速だけど、ちょっと歌う...歌うよ。
Well then. Without further ado, let's... let's sing.
うたうー！
Let's sing!
このクソ熱い真夏日に、一曲、聴いてください。
On this damn hot midsummer day, please listen to this song.
adrenaline!!!
作詞・作曲 中野 領太
Lyrics & Composition: Ryota Nakano
単純な言葉 重ねていく",
Repeating simple words,
もっと 心は素直で
More, with an honest heart.
何でもないような その笑顔が
That seemingly ordinary smile
明日を照らす光に
Turns into light that illuminates tomorrow.
ずっと気づいてたんだって
I've always noticed it,
この手に抱えてたんだって
I've always held it in these hands.
はじけた声に 流した答えが今",
In the bursting voice, the answer I shed is now...
そっと きっと 願い込めた",
...softly, surely, filled with a wish.
ずっと回る回る夢の中で
Always inside a dream that goes round and round,
繰り返し君と踊った
I danced with you over and over.
揺れる景色
The swaying scenery...
イェーイ！
Yay!
道は続く
The road continues...
イェーイ！
Yay!
通り過ぎる風に吹かれ
Blown by the passing wind,
何度も超えて行けるから 境界線
I can cross the boundary line many times.
雲の先 晴れて 手を伸ばした
The sky cleared beyond the clouds, and I reached out my hand.
涙は今
Tears are now...
イェーイ！
Yay!
輝く空に預けて
...left to the shining sky,
走り出すの
I'll start running.
並んで見つけた
We found it side-by-side,
輝く光を手に
holding the brilliant light in our hands.
問題はいつも自分次第
The problem always depends on you.
さあ 未来を選んで
Now, choose your future.
こんがらがった糸ほどいたら
If you untangle the knotted threads,
思いのまま進もう
let's move forward as we please.
毎日冒険なんだって
They say every day is an adventure,
奇跡は無限大なんだって
they say miracles are infinite.
高鳴る想い 羅針盤のように今",
My throbbing heart, like a compass, right now...
そっと きっと 導いてく",
...is softly, surely, guiding me.
空を巡る巡る波に乗って
Riding the waves that go round and round the sky,
風任せ君と笑った
I laughed with you, letting the wind take us.
予想外は
The unexpected is...
イェーイ！
Yay!
想定内
...as expected!
イェーイ！
Yay!
間違いや失敗も楽しんで
Enjoying mistakes and failures,
一歩踏み出した 見えた可能性
the possibility I saw when I took a step forward.
行き止まりの壁壊して
Breaking through the dead-end wall.
まだ知らない
If I'm with you...
イェーイ！
Yay!
世界 君と一緒なら
...in a world I don't know yet...
怖くないよ
...I'm not afraid.
ワクワクしている
I'm so excited,
今が一番大好き
I love the present most of all.
ゆっくり ゆっくり
Slowly, slowly
焦んない 焦んない
No rush, no rush
自分の歩幅で行こう
Let's go at our own pace
大丈夫 大丈夫
It's okay, it's okay
心配ない 心配ない
No worries, no worries
描いたもの 全部叶えるよ
Everything we've envisioned will come true
ずっと回る回る夢の中で
In a dream that keeps spinning and spinning
繰り返し君と踊った
I danced with you over and over again
いつか君と約束した
The promise I made with you someday
願いの架け橋を渡って
I'll cross the bridge of wishes
何度も越えていけるから境界線
Because I can cross the boundary line again and again
雲かき分けて手を伸ばした
I pushed through the clouds and reached out my hand
涙は今 空に預けて走り出すの
Leaving my tears to the sky now, I'll start running
並んで見つけた
Side by side, we found it
輝く光を手に
With the shining light in our hands
ワクワクしている
My heart is pounding
今が一番大好き
I love right now the most
疲れたー！
We're tired!
暑かったねー。
It was hot, wasn't it?
暑かったー。
It was hot.
お疲れ様ー。
Good job, everyone.
ありがとうございまーす。
Thank you very much.
このくそ暑い中ね。
In this crazy heat.
でも足元冷たいよ。
But the water at our feet is cold.
ほら、水に入っちゃお。
Look, let's get in the water.
海の中ビショビショだよ。
It's soaking wet in the ocean.
せっかく海に来たからさ... グラビア写真撮らない？
Since we're at the beach... why don't we take some gravure photos?
あ、いいね。
Oh, sounds good.
こういう感じに決まってるでしょ。
This is how it's done, right?
ここ風呂じゃねーんだよ。
This isn't a bathtub.
ちょっと！みんなでやれば風呂じゃない。
Wait! If we all do it, it's not a bathtub.
みんな集まってー。
Everyone, gather 'round.
団長もよいしょっと。
I'll join in too.
マリン、おっぱい大きいの禁止ね。
Marine, no showing off your big breasts.
じゃあ無理だよ！
Then it's impossible!
お前さー！入水してんじゃねー。
You! Don't just submerge yourself.
どうしたらいいの？
What should I do then?
色気、色気。
Sexiness, sexiness.
色気ー。
Sexiness.
顔持ってきて。フレアもっと前行って。
Bring your faces in. Flare, go further forward.
顔のデカさが...このくらいかな。
The face size... maybe about this much.
おい！余ってんだろ。
Hey! You're crowding me.
余ってんだよ。
You're crowding us.
やだやだやだ！雑魚になっちゃう。
No, no, no! I'll look like a minor character.
全然セクシーじゃないよ、マリン。
That's not sexy at all, Marine.
失礼しました。セクシー見ないよ。
My apologies. You won't see any sexiness.
これが見たかったの？
Is this what you wanted to see?
一人だけ子供が混じってる。
There's one child mixed in.
今多分スクショされてる。
We're probably being screenshotted right now.
お尻を映すな！
Don't show the butt!
お尻映ってないから。
The butt isn't in the shot.
もうちょっと上からいけますか？
Can you go a bit higher?
あ、そうそうそう。
Ah, right, right, right.
ちょい引きいけますこれ？
Can we zoom out a bit for this?
で、ちょっとだけ下の方がいいかな。
And maybe a bit lower would be better.
こういう感じ？セクシー！
Like this? Sexy!
お姉さん組ピチャピチャ。
The big sister group is splashing around.
暑いね。
It's hot.
眩しい！太陽光を誰か加工しておいて。
It's bright! Someone edit the sunlight later.
眩しい感じにしといて。
Make it look bright.
あとはやりたいことある？
Anything else you want to do?
今のポーズやりたかったんだよ。
I really wanted to do that pose.
本当？どうしようかな。
Really? What should I do...
よいしょ。立ち上がって。
Alright. Stand up.
海かー。海のポーズ。
The sea, huh. A sea pose.
え、サメのポーズ。
Uh, a shark pose.
誰が見たいの、それ。
Who wants to see that?
団員さんは見たいはず。
The Knight Brats should want to see it.
エルフレさんも見たいって。
Elfriends want to see it too.
このおっぱいをアップにしたものを。
One with a close-up of these breasts.
ちょっと待て！貯めといたの。
Wait a second! I was saving that.
美しい悲鳴が出ちゃった。
A beautiful scream came out.
ありがとう、写真も。
Thanks for the photos too.
え、何？終わりの空気？
Wait, what? Is this the end?
終わりだよ！バイバイー！
It's the end! Bye-bye!
おや？なんだか呼ばれているような...
Oh? I feel like I'm being called...
誰だろう、この声は。
I wonder whose voice this is.
ちょっと行ってきます！
I'll be right back!
あー！わためー！
Ah! Watame!
フレアは私のものだー！
Flare is mine!
わため！
Watame!
レディースアンドジェントルメン！
Ladies and gentlemen!
ノエール！
Noel!
フレアー！
Flare!
あれ、肝心のフレアがいないんですけど...
Wait, the main star Flare isn't here...
「炎と森のカーニバル」って聞いたんですけど...
I heard it was the "Carnival of Flame and Forest"...
フレアー！
Flare!
どこだー！
Where are you?!
お待たせ！なんか入るタイミング逃したかなって思ってたｗ
Sorry to keep you waiting! I thought I might have missed my cue, lol.
何持ってんの？
What are you carrying?
何だそれは！
What is that?!
これはアコーディオンだ！
This is an accordion!
おお！かっこいい！かっこいい！
Oh! So cool! So cool!
わためは何持ってんの？
Watame, what are you carrying?
大太鼓だ！
It's a bass drum!
これ何？チューバ？
What's this? A tuba?
チューバだよ！ブーー！
It's a tuba! Booo!
うわ、強そう！攻撃力高そう！
Whoa, it looks strong! Its attack power must be high!
やばいよ！ブーー！
It's crazy! Booo!
今日は、みんなでね、楽器をマーチングしながら歌いたい曲があるんだよね！
Today, I have a song that I want us to sing while marching with these instruments!
イエーイ！
Yay!
なに、なに？何を歌うの？
What, what? What are we singing?
この景色見て、ちょっと綺麗じゃない？
Look at this scenery, isn't it beautiful?
美しい...
Beautiful...
湧き潰しもしっかりしてるからねｗ
I've made sure there are no spawns here lol.
やめなｗ でもこの辺とか敵が湧きそうだから...
Stop it lol. But enemies might spawn around here...
やばいね。ガチで見ないで。
That's dangerous. Seriously, don't look.
さあ、みんなで歌おう！タイトルコール！
Now, let's sing together! Title call!
炎と！
Flame and!
森の！
Forest!
カーニバル！
Carnival!
炎と森のカーニバル
作詞・作曲 Fukase
Carnival of Flame and Forest
Lyrics and Composition by Fukase
横浜にある遊園地の
At an amusement park in Yokohama
コスモパニックの非常口が
The emergency exit of Cosmo Panic
このパーティーのエントランス
Is the entrance to this party
扉を開けたらそこは
When you open the door, there is a place
巨大な樹が支配する
Dominated by a giant tree
会場の名はツリーランド
The venue's name is Tree Land
君はここでは大スター
You are a big star here
ほら 鐘が鳴った
Look, the bell has rung
パーティーが始まる
The party begins
炎と森のカーニバル
Carnival of Flame and Forest
ミイラ男も踊ってる
Even the mummy man is dancing
今宵僕が招かれたカーニバル
The carnival I was invited to tonight
魔法使いは
The magician
僕に言ったんだ
Said to me
「この恋は秘密にしておくんだよ」
"Keep this love a secret"
「さもなければ
"Otherwise,
この子の命が
this child's life
危ない」と
will be in danger"
私をパーティーへ連れ出して
Take me out to the party
君がそうやって言うからさ
Because you said so
悪魔のDJを見に行こうか
Shall we go see the devil DJ?
月のカクテルを買ってくるよ
I'll buy a moon cocktail
バーのロボットに見惚れてたら
While I was fascinated by the bar robot
君がそうやって怒るからさ
Because you got angry like that
人目を気にしてキスをした
We kissed, mindful of others' eyes
ほら 君の出番だろう
Look, it's your turn
炎と森のカーニバル
Carnival of Flame and Forest
シンデレラも歌ってる
Cinderella is singing too
今宵僕が招かれたカーニバル
The carnival I was invited to tonight
人混みの中
In the crowd
離れないように
so as not to be separated,
君と手を繋いだんだ
I held your hand
この君の手を
This hand of yours,
もう離さないと僕は
I will never let go again,
決めたんだ
I have decided
炎と森のカーニバル ミイラ男も踊ってる 宵僕ら招かれたカーニバル
At the carnival of fire and forest, even the mummy is dancing. Tonight, the carnival we were invited to.
魔法使いは僕に言ったんだ
The wizard said to me...
この恋は秘密にしておくんだよ
Keep this love a secret.
さもなければこの子の命が危ないと
Otherwise, this child's life will be in danger.
はあ〜！ すごい！
Haa~! Amazing!
どうだった楽器
How was the instrument?
いやこれ重って！
Whoa, this is heavy!
肩凝りそうだね
Looks like your shoulders will get stiff.
凝っちゃうよこれ
They're definitely gonna get stiff!
強いね
You're strong.
いやもう強かったよ
Yeah, it was tough!
うぇーい！
Yay!
よう肺活量持っとる
You've got great lung capacity.
いやー頑張った頑張った
Man, I worked hard, I worked hard.
わためはどう？
How about you, Watame?
腕がー！
My arms!
腕が
My arms...
大変だね
It's tough, isn't it?
みんな疲れたね
Everyone is tired.
ナイス太鼓だったよ
That was nice drumming.
ナイスだよ
Nice job.
ナイスだったよ
It was nice.
強そう
Looks strong.
ドン！ジャン！ダッ！
Don! Jan! Da!
フレアそれ弾けてたのかちゃんと
Flare, were you actually playing that properly?
ちゃんとピロピロ
I was playing it properly.
お〜いいねいいね
Oh, nice, nice.
優雅だね
Elegant, isn't it?
でもね弾くことに夢中になっちゃってこれね
But I got so absorbed in playing this, you know?
そうだね
True.
さてわため
Now, Watame.
ハープはどこへ？
Where did the harp go?
あれ？わため？
Huh? Watame?
ハープ？
Harp?
何のことだ？
What are you talking about?
記憶にないんだった
She has no memory of it.
あれ？あれ？
Huh? Huh?
ハープは捨てた？
Did you throw away the harp?
この中に入ってるんじゃないかな
Maybe it's inside here?
あ、その中に！あ、なるほどね
Oh, inside there! Ah, I see.
そういうことで解決しよう
Let's settle it with that.
まってまって しまってある
Wait, it's stored away.
まということでね せっかくこうして楽器持ってるので
Well, anyway, since we're holding instruments like this...
スクショしませんか
Shall we take a screenshot?
記念撮影！記念撮影！ したいしたい！ぜひぜひ！
Commemorative photo! Commemorative photo! I want to! By all means!
やっぱアップでさマーチング感出したい
I want a close-up to give a marching feel.
あ〜いいじゃんマーチング感！
Ah, sounds good, marching feel!
こう どう？ こう あ、いいじゃんいいじゃん！
Like this. How's this? Like this. Ah, nice, nice!
こう、こう、こう！
Like this, this, this!
どう？どう？
How's this? How's this?
イェーイ！
Yay!
フレアそれ逆だよ あっちだあっちだ
Flare, you're the other way around. Over there, over there.
あ、こっち？
Ah, this way?
チョロっと出てる方
The part that's sticking out a bit.
イェーイ！イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
イェーイ！いい感じいい感じ
Yay! Looking good, looking good.
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
回るな回るな！
Don't spin, don't spin!
イェーイ！イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
良い感じ 撮れたかな
Looking good. Did we get it?
撮れた。撮ってくれましたか
I got it. Did you take it for us?
お〜良いのでは
Oh, isn't it good?
良いのでは！ありがとう二人とも
Isn't it good! Thanks, you two.
いや楽しかったー！
Man, that was fun!
楽しかった！ありがとうございました
It was fun! Thank you very much.
じゃあこのままわため
Well then, continuing on, Watame.
この森で儀式の続きをしよう
Let's continue the ritual in this forest.
儀式の続き？
The continuation of the ritual?
炎と森とわため
Fire, forest, and Watame...
今日は不思議なカーニバル
Today is a mysterious carnival.
さもなければ命が わための命が危ないと
Otherwise, life will... Otherwise, Watame's life will be in danger.
おかしいな〜
That's strange...
ということで色々準備するのでね
Anyway, we're going to prepare various things.
それではこのまま楽しんでくれ
So, please continue to enjoy the show.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
負けないで負けてね
Don't lose, please lose.
負けるよー！
I'll lose!
ありがとう
Thank you.
あ私もなんか呼ばれてるから私も一緒に行くわちょっと
Ah, I'm being called too, so I'll go with you.
あ本当！じゃあ一緒に行こう
Oh, really? Then let's go together.
じゃあおれら行こう！
Then let's go!
行きたくないな〜なんか
I don't really want to go...
行くんだよ
You're going.
やだな〜
I don't want to...
行くよー
Let's go!
こんばんはー！
Good evening!
今宵は不知火フレア2周年記念アニバーサリーライブにお越しいただきありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming to Shiranui Flare's 2nd Anniversary Live tonight!
ホロライブ5期生、尾丸ポルカです！
I'm Omaru Polka from Hololive Gen 5!
すごいね〜後ろまで見えてるよ、みんな！
Wow! I can see all the way to the back, everyone!
後ろまで見えてるよ〜イェーイ！
I can see all the way to the back! Yay!
というわけでね、今フレアが頑張って多分走ってる途中だが
Anyway, Flare is probably in the middle of running hard right now...
うん、そろそろ来るかな、アストライアでも歌っとこうかな
Hmm, I wonder if she'll be here soon. Should I sing Astraea?
よし、じゃあ呼ぶぞ！みんなで行くよ！
Alright, then I'll call her! Everyone, let's go!
じゃあ呼ぶからね。何て呼ぼう。フレアでいいや。
I'm going to call her. What should I call her? 'Flare' is fine.
せーの！
One, two...
フレーアー！
FLARE-!
あれ？
Huh?
フレーアー！
FLARE-!
あれ？なんかまだ到着していない…
Huh? She hasn't arrived yet...
あ、あの、
Ah, um...
あの、森からこな、来るはずだったんだけど。
Um, I was supposed to come from the forest...
森から、え？
From the forest, eh?
待機中のみなさんの！
To everyone waiting!
もっともっと大きな声で！
With a much, much louder voice!
せーの！
Ready, set...
フレアーーー！
Flare---!
あーい！
Heeey!
お芝居、どうもありがとうございました！
Thank you very much for the skit!
あ、じゃあ前座の私はこれにて帰らせて…
Ah, well then, this opening act will be taking her leave...
帰るな帰るな！
Don't leave, don't leave!
お疲れ様。
Good job.
なんか繋ぎだった、ええでしょ。
It was like a transition, it's fine.
いや、実は、今日初めて会うんですよね。
No, actually, we're meeting for the first time today, right?
はじめまして、どうもありがとう…
Nice to meet you, thank you very...
はじめまして。
Nice to meet you.
前座、ありがとうございました。
Thank you for the opening act.
前座、お疲れ様でした。
Good job on the opening act.
しーーっ！
Shhh!
言っちゃダメなんです、今はね、
You shouldn't say that, right now,
かっこいい子とする、かっこいい子と。
I'm with a cool kid, a cool kid.
最高にね、かっこいいことするからあんまり喋らないでくれる？歌うときまで。
We're going to do something really cool, so could you not talk much? Until we sing.
もうだいぶ喋ったがな！
We've already talked quite a bit!
じゃあ、かっこいい歌、歌っちゃいますか？
Well then, shall we sing a cool song?
あ、じゃあ、かっこいい曲歌っちゃいますか？
Ah, well then, shall we sing a cool song?
女の子二人でかっこいい歌歌っちゃいますか？
Shall we two girls sing a cool song?
歌っちゃいます！
We shall!
盛り上がっていけよ！
Let's get hyped!
いけよ！
Let's go!
はい！
Yes!
タイトルコールさせてもらいます。
I'll do the title call.
はい。
Yes.
不死鳥のフランメ。
Fushichou no Flamme.
不死鳥のフランメ
Fushichou no Flamme
まさか二人　今世界は
Who would've thought, the two of us... Now the world
ひとつになる
Becoming one
轟き給え
Let it roar
奏でたまえ
Let it play
さあ始まろう
Now, let it begin
3, 2, 1 Ready go!
振れ果てなき
Swinging endlessly
強いこの想いは譲れない
This strong feeling I won't give up
誰にも負けぬ
Won't lose to anyone
不死なるメロディ
The immortal melody
輝け　燃えろ
Shine, burn
研ぎ澄ます　零れ出した
Sharpening, it spilled out
命紡いだ鼓動を
The heartbeat that spun life
翳した　Moonlight その光は
Held up Moonlight, that light is
残した者に何を問う
What does it ask of those who remain?
哀しみを束ねて
Bundling the sadness
次に刃に
Next to the blade
Justiceの名の許
Under the name of Justice
二度と消える事ない　魂の種火をさあ灯そう
Now, let's light the spark of the soul that will never fade again
燃えなさい
Burn
傷に　定めなどない
To the wounds, there is no destiny
跳びなさい
Jump
ここを　引き千行け
Tear through here
舞いなさい
Dance
熱く羽ばたき合い
Flapping wings hotly together
響き合う　重なり合う　絆
Resonating, overlapping bonds
さあ　涙握りしめて
Now, clenching the tears
全部握りしめて
Clenching everything
目映くなる夢を羽に
With the dazzling dream as wings
願う明日と共に
Together with the tomorrow we wish for
翔ばないか　歌え不死鳥
Shall we not fly? Sing, Phoenix
舞い生きて　見上げた空
Dancing and living, the sky I looked up at
零さぬようにときめいた
Heart throbbed so as not to spill
砂のいざなう　数多の汗
The sand inviting, numerous sweats
噛み締め契り上を向け
Gritting teeth, make a vow, look up
震えるくらいなら
If it's enough to make you tremble
決意を構えて
Prepare your resolve
Nightmareを断ち切って
Cutting off the Nightmare
断罪を審判う　終焉の鉄槌をさあ落とそう
Now, let's drop the hammer of the end that judges condemnation
勇気は
Courage
君を　裏切らない
Won't betray you
抱きなさい
Embrace
明日を　信じ抜いて
Believing in tomorrow until the end
満ちなさい
Be filled
輝き出す　煌めき出す　未来
The future that starts to shine, starts to sparkle
そう　心ひとつにして
Yes, making our hearts one
今を束ね　ひとつにして
Bundling the present, making it one
夢描いた夢を羽に
With the dream we dreamed as wings
手と手を繋ぎ　翼にしよう
Let's join hands and make them wings
翔け不死鳥
Fly, Phoenix
もっと... ぜーー！
More...!
イグニッション
Ignition
燃えなさい
Burn
自分に定めなどない
I have no destiny
刻みなさい
Carve it
覚悟生き地獄
Determination, a living hell
響きなさい... 羽ばたきあい
Resonate... flapping wings together
吹き荒ぶ風
The wind that blows wildly
切ない絆
A painful bond
そう... 涙握りしめて
Yes... clutching the tears
背負った全部握りしめて
Clutching everything on my shoulders
今失わぬ夢を放ち
Releasing a dream I won't lose now
願う明日と共に... 止まらないか
Together with the desired tomorrow... Won't it stop?
天を焦がせ
Scorch the heavens
歌えフェニックス... ぜーー！
Sing, Phoenix...!
ふー、はー、今のんで全部使い切ったわ。
Whew... I used up everything I had just now.
結構お疲れなんですね、ポル... ポルカも。
You look quite exhausted, Pol... Polka too.
もう... 限界なんだわ。
I'm... at my limit.
あんまり結構限界に見えてないけど。
You don't really look that close to your limit though.
あのね、あのね、私、かっこいい曲苦手なわけよ。
Listen, listen, I'm not good at cool songs.
はい、はい。なので、ちょっと今日、最初で最後のかっこいい曲なわけ。
Yes, yes. So today was the first and last cool song for me.
はい。何その、どういう動き？ どういう動き、それ？
Right. What's that movement? What's with that movement?
いや、もう、すごく楽しかったけど、ちょっとね...
No, it was a lot of fun, but well...
すごいね、やっぱり。
You're amazing after all.
コストも高かったし。
The cost was high, too.
あの... 揃わねえんだよ、全然。
Um... we're not in sync at all.
ポルカが、いつも「こっちかな」と思ったら「こっち」なわけ。
Whenever I think Polka is going 'this way', she goes 'that way'.
いや、外に広がるだろ、普通考えて。
No, normally you'd branch outwards.
焦っちゃって、なんか全然同じ方向行っちゃうんだから、もういいんだよ。
I got flustered and ended up going in the same direction, so whatever.
もう歌ってる時、そんな記憶ないもん、ポルカ。
I have no memory of that while I was singing.
必死に「あーー！」ってやってた。
I was desperately going 'Ahhh!'
いや、でもかっこよかったよ。
No, but it was cool.
いや、かっこよかったっす。
No, it was cool.
よくハモれるなって思ってました、ポルカ。
I was thinking, "You harmonize so well, Polka."
いや、もう、必死ですよ。
No, I'm just giving it my all.
え、なんかさ、ぶつかる時、すごい難しくない？
Eh, doesn't it feel really difficult when we collide?
本当にね、必死だよ。
Really, I'm doing my best.
いや、この曲を歌いたかったんよ、ポルカと。
No, I really wanted to sing this song with you, Polka.
あ、これね。かっこいい。あ、私はね...
Ah, this one. It's cool. Ah, for me...
あ、こんなになんだろう、「イグニッション」っていうところも全然知らなかったから。
Ah, I didn't even know there was a part like 'Ignition' at all.
イグニッション！ 知らなかったんだ。
Ignition! You didn't know.
サビのすごい有名だなっていうところは知ってたんだけど、イグニッションは知らなかったから、めっちゃ滾ったわ。
I knew the chorus was really famous, but I didn't know about 'Ignition', so I was really hyped.
いや、そう。あの、この曲ともう一曲ね、ちょっと迷ってたやつがあったのよね。
Yeah, that's right. Well, there was another song I was torn between.
有名っすよね、ちょっと。
It's quite famous, isn't it?
そうそうそう。そっちも知ってました。
Right, right, right. I knew that one too.
「不撓不屈」って... あ、言っちゃった。言っちゃった。
'Futou Fukutsu'... Ah, I said it. I said it.
言っちゃったね。
You sure did.
いや、そっちもね、すごい... え？ 歌う？ あ、機会があったら...
No, that one too is great... Eh? Singing it? Ah, if there's a chance...
あ、機会があったらね。
Ah, if there's a chance.
ていうか、なんかあの、フランメはさ、逆のパートとか興味ないの？
By the way, are you interested in singing the opposite parts for Flamme?
えっ、ちょっ、え、そのサビのなんか、あの音どうなってるんですか？
Eh, wait, eh, how does that sound in the chorus go?
自分のパートに必死でさ、あの、相手のハモリって一体どうなってるんですかって。
I was so focused on my own part, I was wondering what on earth the other's harmony was like.
ハモリ、教えてくれる？
Will you teach me the harmony?
いいよ。
Sure.
あ、そしたら、そんならええか。
Ah, well then, that's fine.
聞きたいよね、みんな、フレアのさ、高音。
Everyone wants to hear it, right? Flare's high notes.
聞きたいよね、ポルカのハモリ。
Everyone wants to hear it, right? Polka's harmony.
それはいいや。
I'm good on that.
なんでだよ！ 世界一ハモリに向いてない...
Why?! "The world's least suited for harmony"...
そんなことない！ そんなことない！
That's not true! That's not true!
まあ、共演初めてだったのに、本当にありがとうございました。
Well, even though it was our first time performing together, thank you so much.
これからもまたよろしくお願いします。
I look forward to working with you again.
なんなんだよ、この社会人風なやつ。
What's with this formal, business-like tone?
ツーショットは？
How about a two-shot photo?
あ、ツーショット。
Ah, a two-shot.
みんな撮ってぜ。ツーショット、どんな感じで撮りたい？
Everyone, take some photos. How should we pose for the two-shot?
う、これ。ジャンガ、ジャンガ、ジャンガ...
Uh, this. Janga, janga, janga...
同じ方向、やっぱ同じ方向なんだな。
The same direction, we're going in the same direction after all.
ここほどアンバランスな...
We're so unbalanced...
あ、いいんじゃない？ これ、どう？
Ah, isn't this good? How's this?
これが、弟子と師匠の最初で最後の...
This is the first and last of the student and master...
なんかこれ隠してるみたい、スカートの。
It looks like I'm hiding something under my skirt.
師匠を下から持ち上げる、持ち上げる。
Lifting the master from below, lifting her.
よし。あ、じゃあ、あの、こんな感じで、ポルカはけるんで、記念写真これでいいっす。
Alright. Then, Polka is going to head out now, so this commemorative photo is fine.
あ、お疲れ様でした。
Ah, good job.
あ、本当にそれでええんか。
Ah, is that really okay?
え、何が？ いや、でもありがとうございました。
Eh, what? No, but thank you very much.
これからもフレアのライブいっぱい楽しんでけよ！
Keep enjoying Flare's live shows to the fullest!
楽しんでけよ！ ありがとう、おまるポルカでした。
Enjoy them! Thank you, this was Omaru Polka.
ひょーい、頑張ってね。
Hyooi! Good luck!
はい、ありがとう、ポルカ。
Yes, thank you, Polka.
黄色い悲鳴が...
High-pitched cheers...
ちょっと、最後に事件性のある悲鳴出してもらっていい？
Wait, can you give me one last scream that sounds like a crime scene?
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
はー、はい、ありがとうございました。
Whew... yes, thank you very much.
いやー、濃かったな。最後のポルカのやつ、ちょっと事件性がありすぎるな。
Man, that was intense. Polka's scream at the end sounded way too much like a crime.
あー面白かった。
Ah, that was fun.
いや、みんなもどうだった？
So, how did you all like it?
今回のね、あのゲスト、ゲスト枠はこれで全員なんですけれども...
Well, that's all for the guest performances this time...
普段仲良くしていただいてる方を今回お呼びさせていただきました。
I invited those I usually get along well with this time.
みんな、本当にありがとうね！
Everyone, thank you so much!
遊びに来てくれて、一緒に歌ってくれて、本当にありがとうねー！
Thank you so much for coming and singing with me!
ということでね、ここからは、またソロパートに戻っていきます。
So, from here on, we're going back to the solo part.
私一人になってしまったけれども...
I'm by myself now, but...
みんなも一緒に盛り上がってくれたら嬉しいです！
...I'd be happy if everyone gets excited with me!
えー、次の曲はですね...
Um, the next song is...
ガッシュから、あの、「金色のガッシュベル!!」から...
...from Gash, um, from "Zatch Bell!"...
えー、エンディングテーマ、歌いたいなと思っております。
...um, I'd like to sing the ending theme.
聞いてください。
Please listen.
「つよがり」。
"Tsuyogari".
つよがり / 作詞 福田 哲也 / 作曲 緒 誠二
Show of Strength / Lyrics: Tetsuya Fukuda / Composition: Seiji Ko
放課後の校舎 柔らかな光
The school building after school, the soft light...
長い影二つ 寄り添い少し照れてる
Two long shadows, snuggling together, feeling a little shy.
泣きたいくせに 平気な顔で
Even though you want to cry, with an unperturbed face...
胸を張る君を 頼りにしてるよ
...you puff out your chest, and I'm counting on you.
つよがりじゃなくて 素直な気持ち
It's not a show of strength, just my honest feelings...
見せてほしいよ 私だけに
...I want you to show me, only to me.
深呼吸して そんなに解けない言葉
Take a deep breath, words that aren't so easily unraveled...
君が大好き
I love you.
忘れないでいて 誰かが聞いたら
Please don't forget, if someone asks...
笑い飛ばされてもいい 輝く君だけの夢
...it's okay to be laughed at, your own shining dream.
生まれ変わっても 必ず
Even if we're reborn, for sure...
出会える二人だよ そう信じてる
...the two of us will meet again, that's what I believe.
諦めないで 約束だから
Please don't give up, because it's a promise...
私も少し つよがりだね
...I'm also a little bit of a "show of strength", aren't I?
二人が描く それぞれの未来に 向かって
Heading towards the respective futures that the two of us imagine...
走って行こう
...let's run together.
つよがりじゃなくて 素直な気持ち
It's not a show of strength, just my honest feelings...
見せてほしいよ 私だけに
...I want you to show me, only to me.
深呼吸して そんなに解けない言葉
Take a deep breath, words that aren't so easily unraveled...
君が大好き
I love you.
はー！ありがとうございましたー！
Whew! Thank you very much!
なんかずっと、あのコラボパートだったから、
Since it's been all collaboration parts until now,
なんかソロになるとちょっとまたいっそう緊張しましたー！
being solo again makes me feel even more nervous!
あとね、あと一曲だけあるんですけど、
I have one more song left, but before that,
あのその前に、あの、やっぱりちょっとね、あの二周年ということで、宣伝してもいいですか？
since it's my 2nd anniversary, may I do a little promotion?
みんなも、ちょっと待ってたかもしれないなって、
Maybe you guys were waiting for this...
あの、みんな言っただろうかね、『貯めとけよ』って、言ったよな！
I told you all to "save up," didn't I? I definitely did!
ということで、グッズ出ます！ドーン！
So, here come the goods! Ta-da!
不知火フレア 活動二周年記念
Shiranui Flare 2nd Anniversary Celebration
不知火フレア活動二周年記念グッズ！ドンドンパフパフ！
Shiranui Flare 2nd Anniversary Celebration Goods! *fanfare*
ま、こちらのね、内容、見ていきたいですけれども、順番に行きましょう。ダダダドーン！
Well, let's take a look at what's inside, one by one. *drumroll*
不知火フレア 活動二周年記念 商品構成
Shiranui Flare 2nd Anniversary Celebration Product Lineup
えっと、不知火フレア活動二周年、え、商品構成。え、まず販売ですね、こちらなんと...
Um, Shiranui Flare 2nd Anniversary product lineup. First of all, regarding sales, what do we have here...
これ数量限定の、あれ...ま、これちょっと後で触れましょうかね。これはちょっと後にしましょう。
This is a limited quantity one... well, let's talk about this later. Let's save this for later.
なんとですね、今回、あの単品販売があります！
Guess what? This time, we have individual items for sale!
いつもはね、あの全部、全部セットじゃないとグッズ買えないよーっていうのが多かったんですけど、ちょっと今回はですね、あの分けてみました。
Usually, you often couldn't buy goods unless you bought the whole set, but this time, I've made them available separately.
なんでね、あの、『いや、これは欲しかったけど、こっちはちょっといらないな』みたいな、もうそういうのもあるかもしれないんですけどね。ま、全部買ってくれたら一番嬉しいんですけどね。
So, even if you think, "I want this one, but I don't really need that one," that's okay. Though, I'd be happiest if you bought them all!
で、ちなみにですね、ボイス単品販売なんですけど、これの一番上の、あの「私から君へ二周年を数えて感謝のメッセージ」、
By the way, regarding the individual voice sales, the first one, "A message of gratitude to you as we mark two years,"
これね、あの私からの、あの、お手紙、ボイスメッセージ、みたいな感じになっております。
is like a voice letter or message from me.
私のシンプルな、あの気持ちを、あの、エルフレのみんなに、あの、聞いてもらいたいなって思います。
I want all the Elfriends to hear my simple, heartfelt feelings.
ま、ちょっとボイスドラマ形式にな、感じのちょっと始まりはあるんですけど、あの、こちらですね...
It starts off a bit like a voice drama, but here we have...
メガネ、えーと、「BIGメガネ置きアクリルスタンド」をお迎えに置くと、ちょっと照れくさい感じになるかもしれないですね。
If you set up the "BIG Glasses Holder Acrylic Stand," it might feel a little embarrassing.
ま、どんなデザインかはちょっと後で見ましょう。
We'll check the design later.
あの、ちなみに、あの、なんか『罵倒されたいボイス』みたいな、あの、生きてる人が辛くなるやつこれね、お前らが求めたんだからな！
By the way, about the "Wants to be verbally abused" voice, the one that makes living people suffer... you guys were the ones who asked for it!
ま、ちょっとこれに関しては、あの、私は悪くない、私は悪くないからな！
Well, as for that, it's not my fault! I'm not to blame!
ということをちょっと言っておきながら、あとはもうあの、全肯定なんで、次に行きましょう。
Saying that, the rest are all "all-affirming" ones, so let's move on.
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
気になった方はぜひ買ってください。え、「フルセット購入特典」、こちら、え、直筆サイン入りポストカード。こちら数量限定になっております。
If you're interested, please buy them. Next, the "Full Set Purchase Bonus": an autographed postcard. This one is limited in quantity.
あの、サイン、もしかしたら変わるかもって言ったんですけど、
I mentioned before that the signature might change,
あの今回はですね、あの販売した段階でのこちらのサインになっておりますので、「変わらないやんけー！」みたいな。
but this time, it's the signature from the time of sale, so you might be like, "It hasn't changed at all!"
ということでですね、ぜひぜひ、もし欲しいよーって思ってくださる方がいたらね、あの購入してください。
So, if anyone really wants one, please go ahead and purchase it.
こちらですね、あの前回の生誕祭の時と同じ量、あの、ご用意しております。だから、結構な量ご用意させていただいております。
We've prepared the same amount as the previous birthday festival. So, quite a large quantity is available.
で、生誕祭のね、あのサインも書き終わっておりますので、順次皆さんのところには発送がそろそろ行くのではないかなと思いますので、こちらをよろしくお願いします。
I've also finished signing the birthday festival ones, so shipping should be starting soon. Please look forward to it.
はい、そしてですね、え、次に行きますよ。このポストカード、なんとタペストリーになります！
Alright, and moving on. This postcard illustration will also be available as a tapestry!
B2タペストリー
B2 Tapestry
父様が書いてくれました！可愛いでしょ、飾って！
My "Father" drew it! Isn't it cute? Please display it!
私がタペストリーを出すのは結構珍しいんですよ。
It's quite rare for me to release a tapestry.
なのでぜひぜひ、こちら購入してくださいね。次！
So please, definitely get this one. Next!
BIGメガネ置きアクリルスタンド
BIG Glasses Holder Acrylic Stand
こちら「アクリルスタンド」、これメガネをね、かけられるんですよ。こちらサクミチ先生にですね、お願いしました！
This "Acrylic Stand" can actually hold glasses. I commissioned Sakumichi-sensei for this one!
見てみて、可愛いでしょー！
Look at it, isn't it cute!
こちらもぜひぜひね、あの買ってメガネをかけてくれたら、メガネをかける私を見れるかもね。はい次！
Please buy it and let it hold your glasses, then you might see me wearing them. Next!
え、こちら「ウォールマグ」。これは結構あの、会社、社畜の皆さんに、お役立ちいただけるのではないでしょうか。
Next is the "Wall Mug." I think this will be very useful for all the "corporate drones" out there.
ウォールマグ
Wall Mug
おしゃれなデザインをちょっと目指してみました。
I aimed for a stylish design.
女の子もね、持ち運べますよ。
Girls can carry it too.
ぜひぜひ、こちら全て、あの単品でも販売しておりますので、ぜひぜひこちらもお手にとってくれたら嬉しいです。
All of these items are also available separately, so I'd be happy if you'd take a look.
グッズ以上です！
That's all for the goods!
でですね、まだまだちょっと告知したいことがあるので、ちょっと巻きな感じでいくんですけど。
Now, I still have more things I want to announce, so I'll go through them quickly.
ま、ライブ、これで、あと一曲歌ったら終わりなんですけど...
As for the live performance, there's only one song left after this, but...
もうちょっと「アンコール！アンコール！」って、あの、セルフで、勝手にもうアンコールは...
But I'll just go "Encore! Encore!" myself, so the encore is already...
...をつくってしまったんですけど、
...but I ended up making one,
あの、どうしても歌いたかった曲が１曲ありまして、
there's one song I really wanted to sing,
そちらでちょっとあの、予約してある枠、このあと10時15分から公開になります。
and the reserved slot for it will be public after this at 10:15 PM.
こちら！
This one!
『オツキミリサイタル』！
"Otsukimi Recital"!
こちらをね、どうしても歌いたかったんですよ。
I really, really wanted to sing this one.
なので、頑張る君を何度でも支えてあげたい、そんな１曲になっております。
It's a song for supporting you who's doing your best, over and over again.
ぜひぜひ、こっちも聴いてください。これもライブ映像となっております。
Please, please listen to this too. It's also live footage.
歌ってみたではありません。今回のライブの延長戦ということで、
It's not just a cover video. Consider it an extension of today's live,
アンコールとして聴いてください。
and please listen to it as an encore.
で、ですね、あの、もう一個...
And then, one more thing...
なんかあの『？？？』って書いてあった謎の枠が立ってたと思うんですけど、
I think there was a mysterious slot titled "???" that was set up,
これはね、あの、ちょっと、あの、これは一体、あの、何者なんだみたいな...
everyone was wondering like, "What on earth could this be?"...
予測してる人とかいたけど、どうすんのこれ、全然関係なかったらっていうね。
People were making predictions, but what if it was completely unrelated? (laughs)
ということで、こちら上がります！
Anyway, this is what's being uploaded!
『怪物』！
"Kaibutsu"!
こちら、お楽しみに待っててくれたかなと思うので、
I think many of you have been looking forward to this,
こちら、22時30分から上がります。
so this will be uploaded at 10:30 PM.
なのでアンコール聴いてから、ぜひぜひ『怪物』も聴いてください！
So after listening to the encore, please listen to "Kaibutsu" too!
ということで、あの、動画めちゃくちゃ凄いです。
By the way, the video is absolutely incredible.
山崎先生にあのイラスト描いていただいたんですけど、動画も凄いことになっているので、
Yamasaki-sensei drew the illustration, and the video itself is also amazing,
ぜひぜひ見てくださいね！
so please check it out!
では、あの、ちょっと時間もないので、ラスト一曲聴いてください。
Well, we're running out of time, so please listen to the last song.
あの、オリジナルではないんですけど、ラスト一曲、いい曲、泣ける曲で、
It's not an original, but the last one is a wonderful, moving song,
カバーソング一曲聴いてください。ではいきましょう！
so please listen to this cover song. Here we go!
『BOYS BE BRAVE ～少年よ勇気を持て～』...
"BOYS BE BRAVE ~Shonen yo Yuki wo Mote~"...
待って、
Wait,
勇気を持て。
Have courage.
あきらめるものは全部
Everything you give up on,
もらう時は一つだけ
is just one thing when you receive it.
五分プラス笑顔は 愛され上手
Five minutes plus a smile makes you lovable.
長いものに巻かれてゆくほうが 楽でも
Even if it's easier to just go with the flow,
YES NO はっきりさせなきゃ曖昧ね
If you don't say YES or NO clearly, it's ambiguous.
弱気はブルンブルン 嘘が咲く
Timidity goes vroom-vroom, and lies bloom.
お願いするのは全部
Everything you wish for,
叶えられるのは一つ
only one can be granted.
順序を欠く感謝は 幸せ上手
Gratitude out of order makes you good at being happy.
意地っ張りだって叩きすぎたなら 壊れる
Even stubbornness breaks if it's pushed too far.
YES NO はっきりさせなきゃ凍りそう
If you don't say YES or NO clearly, it'll freeze up.
強気にはウイウイ 花が咲く
For the strong-willed, ooh-ooh, flowers bloom.
君の選ぶ夢を 誰かに頼っちゃいけない
You mustn't rely on anyone else for the dream you choose.
決して自分に
A heart that
負けない心
never loses to itself.
BOYS BE BRAVE 勇気を手にして
BOYS BE BRAVE, grab hold of courage.
傷つけることは得意
You're good at hurting others,
あきらめるのは簡単
giving up is easy.
後悔マイナス時は 真剣勝負
Subtracting regret makes it a serious match.
歩いてみなくちゃ犬だって棒に 当たれない
If you don't take a step, you'll never hit the mark.
YES NO はっきりさせなきゃ夕方
If you don't say YES or NO clearly, it'll be evening.
あの子がスイスイ 歌い出す
That girl starts singing smoothly.
強い向かい風に 負けずに足を 踏み出そう
Let's step forward without losing to the strong headwind.
明日を信じ
A heart that continues
続ける心
to believe in tomorrow.
BOYS BE BRAVE...
BOYS BE BRAVE ～少年よ勇気を持って～
BOYS BE BRAVE ~Boy, have courage~
#不知火フレア2周年記念ライブ
#ShiranuiFlare2ndAnniversaryLive
BRAVE
勇気を手に
With courage in hand
へへーい！不知火フレアちゃんでーす！
Hehe-i! It's Shiranui Flare-chan!
そこの綺麗なお姉さん、お兄様！
You beautiful ladies and gentlemen over there!
オレと一緒に合いの手してほしいかもー！
I'd like you to do some calls with me!
ホイ！
Hoi!
おー、みんな上手だぞー！
Oh, you're all so good at it!
どうも、ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
君の歩く道作ろう
Let's make the path you walk
誇らしい地図を
A map to be proud of
世界中でたった一つの BOYS BE BRAVE
The only BOYS BE BRAVE in the whole world
勇気を手に
With courage in hand
BOYS BE BRAVE 勇気を手に
BOYS BE BRAVE, with courage in hand
不知火フレア 2nd Anniversary Live! ～みんなで沢山盛り上がろう！～
Shiranui Flare 2nd Anniversary Live! ~Let's all have a blast together!~